# Yuan LYU

# **UX/Interaction Designer**

### **EXPERIENCE**

- UX/UI Design Intern, Volkswagen AG
  Smart Mobility&Transport, Berlin, Germany
  Oct.2018 ~ Present
  - Iterate the UX design based on user research feedback
  - Master the persona profile, customer journey, user flow of product
  - Create the UI library for the style guide, redesign the landing page
  - Innovation Intern, F. Hoffmann La-Roche AG Finance, Diagnostics IT, Basel, Switzerland Nov.2017 ~ Apr. 2018
    - Contributed to key projects(SAP, personalized healthcare) as UX Designer, designed concepts, created wireframes, etc.
    - Designed and implemented the UCD curriculum, drove cross-team knowledge building agenda on usability
    - Created and facilitated Design Sprint workshop
  - Master Thesis Student, Technische Universität Berlin
    Quality and Usability Lab, Berlin, Germany Jul.2017 ~ May.2018

    Concept Design for Pedestrian-Vehicle Communication in the Age
    of Autonomous Driving
    - Product Design Working Student, Care Campanion GmbH.

      Product Team, Berlin, Germany

      Jul.2017 ~ Oct.2017
      - Concepting and designing for main website and new landing page
      - Analyzing user journey, preparing&executing user research activities
      - Co-operating with senior designer, product managers and developer
    - Product Support Working Student, Jovoto GmbH.

Product Team, Berlin, Germany

*Mar.*2017 ~ *May.*2017

- Created user flows and wireframes for products concept papers
- Technically translated internal as well as external bug reports
- Validated and enriched bug reports with all needed information
- **UX Intern**, FOTILE Kitchen Ware Co. Ltd.

Innovation Institute, Ningbo, China

Oct.2014 ~ Jan.2015

- Co-designed interface for new oven, steam box and microwave oven
- Implement the high-fidelity Prototype individually
- Made reasonable user test script, participated in usability research

## **EDUCATION**

Master of Science in Human Computer Interaction and Design

Double Degree Degree EIT Digital Merit Scholarship 2016/2017

Technische Universität Berlin, Germany

Oct.2016 ~ Present

Université Paris-Sud, France

Sep.2015 ~ Jun.2016

**Bachelor of Engineering in Network Engineering** 

Dalian Maritime University, China

Sep.2011 ~ Jun.2015

- **+49(0)157-3326-2956**
- yuan.lyu@hotmail.com
- http://yuan-lyu.com
- Berlin, Germany 10963

## **PROFILE**

As a hybrid UX designer with programming experiences, I am adept at understanding of user story, and always have the passion to use my creativity to solve unusual problems and design for uncommon products.

Sincerely look forward to the position in the area of UX and Interaction Design.

## **SKILLS**

#### **DESIGN**

In-Depth Interview
Questionnaire
Persona | Scenario
Conceptual Storyboard
Wireframing
Prototyping
Usability Test
Sketch / Photoshop
Axure / InVision / Principle
Balsamiq / OmniGraffle

#### **PROGRAMMING**

JAVA / C#
HTML / CSS / JavaScript
Bootstrap
ASP.NET
SQL Server / MySQL
Unity (Virtual Reality)
Arduino / Processing
Node.js

#### **LANGUAGE**

Chinese: Native English: Fluent German: Beginner